Susan Caperna Lloyd collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 18: Other folk life projects
  - Subseries 9: Morocco and Spain
    - Cultures of Morocco, May 2011, afc2018064_dc001; 1-4, Ferry to Tangier on Straits of Gibraltar; 5, 8, 42-45, Tangier Islamic architectures; 6, Tangier Islamic architecture. The building houses the first property outside the United States which also became the first U.S. embassy in 1821; 7, Susan Lloyd on balcony overlooking Tangier and part of the medina; 9-13, 32-41, Inside Tangier medina; 14-18, 20-26, 30-31, Tangier street culture; 19, Tangier portrait studio window displaying ethnic portraits; 27-29, Miami Beach Restaurant on Tangier beach.; 45 still image files (jpg)
    - Architecture of Spain, December 2011, afc2018064_dc001; 1-2, 73-74, 78-79, The Alhambra was built in the ninth century as a palace and fortress complex incorporating Islamic design then rebuilt in the thirteenth century by the Emirate of Granada; 3-52, La Pedrada (meaning The Quarry because of its rough-hewn nature) is an apartment building and the last civic creation by architect Antonio Gaudi in Barcelona between 1906 and 1912. He used forms from nature and folk art in his fantastical buildings; 53-71, La Sagrada Familia (The Sacred Family) combines Art Nouveau and Gothic styles in a basilica of fantastic design by Antonio Gaudi. He worked on it until his death in 1926 and it is still under construction and a World Heritage UNESCO site; 72, The home of writer Garcia Lorca who legitimized flamenco and gypsy (Roma) culture in his poetry and music. He was murdered in the Spanish Civil War in 1938; 75, View of the Albaicin Arab Quarter from the Alhambra in Granada; 76, Detail of barrio quarter in the Alhambra; 77, View of Granada from the Alhambra; 80-112, Detail of intricate stalactite plaster and stucco design as well as tile work incorporated in the Alhambra.; 112 still image files (jpg)
    - Spanish Flamenco dance, December 2011, afc2018064_dc001; 1-8, Flamenco star Jose Galvan with young student outside his studio in Seville; 9, Young flamenco dancer, student of Jose Galvan, Seville; 10, Jose Galvan in his studio in Seville; 11-15, Flamenco club in Grenada; 16-48, Venta El Gallo flamenco club, Sacromonte, Granada; 49-51, Carmen de las Cuevas flamenco school, Granada.; 51 still image files (jpg)
    - Salobreno, Spain, December 2011, afc2018064_dc001; 1, Sun bather on Salobreno beach; 2, Fishing on Salobreno Beach; 3, Dog on Salobreno Beach; 4, Sunset on Salobreno Beach; 5-7, Home decorated on outside walls with blue and white Talavera folk pottery which was influenced by Ming Dynasty imports; 8, Salobreno sits atop rock mound overlooking Mediterranean Sea; 9-12, tenth century Moorish castle overlooking Mediterranean Sea; 13, Restaurant sign with wrought-iron folk depiction of Don Quixote on horse.; 13 still image files (jpg)
  - Subseries 10: Nicaragua
    - Jaripeo bull riding, February 2014, afc2018064_dc001; 1-39, Jaripeo is a form of bull riding practiced mainly in Central and Southern Mexico that developed in the sixteenth century by Spaniards.; 39 still image files (jpg)
    - Lake Nicaragua, February 2014, afc2018064_dc001; 1-3, Boy displays mounted shark teeth from fresh water Lake Nicaragua; 4-13, Boat trip on Lake Nicaragua; 14-15, Banyon tree on lake shore; 16, Family on Lake Nicaragua shore; 17-19, Trip on vintage boat to Ometepe Island on Lake Nicaragua; 20-33, Finca Santo Domingo in traditional rustic style on Ometepe Island on Lake Nicaragua; 34-36, Natural spring on Ometepe Island on Lake Nicaragua; 37-44, Villagers on foothills of Concepcion Volcano on Ometepe Island on Lake Nicaragua.; 44 still image files (jpg)
    - Sandinista folklore, February 2014, afc2018064_dc001; 1-7, FSLN Gallery of photos of missing or murdered in Contra War; 8, 98, Nicaraguan Sandinista; 9-19, Museum of Legends and Traditions in Leon Nicaragua; 20-21, Statue of young Sandinista at Museum of Legends and Traditions in leon Nicaragua; 22, Marker honoring fallen Sandinistas Edgard Alvarez at Museum of Legends and Traditions in Leon Nicaragua; 23-24, Legend of the Tamarind Tree recognizing indigenous resistance in Leon Nicaragua; 25-56, Museum of the Revolution in Leon Nicaragua; 57-61, Skateboarders and mural of the Sandinista Revolution; 62-65, Wall mural in Leon Nicaragua to the Martyrs of the Revolution and folk hero Sandino; 66, Portraits of folk heroes Che Guevara and Sandino in Nicaragua restaurant; 67, Wall mural portrait of folk hero Sandino in Leon Nicaragua; 68-73, Leon wall mural depicting Nicaraguan Revolution and folklore; 74-77, Mural in Leon Nicaragua basketball court depicting Sandinista Revolution; 78, Magazine newsstand in Leon Nicaragua featuring folk heroes Che Guevara and Daniel Ortego and others such as Cesar Chavez and Yaseer Arafat; 79-82, 89-92, Matagalpa cemetery contains the graves of the fallen FSLN and was a stronghold of the Sandinista Revolution; 83-88, Brother of a fallen Sandinista visiting Matagalpa cemetery which contains the graves of the fallen FSLN. Matagalpa was a stronghold to the Sandinista Revolution; 95-96, Che Guevara and Sandino mural in café on Lake Nicaragua; 97, Daniel Ortega poster in Leon.; 98 still image files (jpg)
    - Santos folk art, February 2014, afc2018064_dc001; 1-57, Antique santos folk art saint statues in Nicaragua.; 57 still image files (jpg)
    - Street culture of Leon, February 2014, afc2018064_dc001; 1-2, Lion monument dedicated to Ruben Dario in front of Leon Nicaragua cathedral. Dario is famed poet of Nicaragua; 3, Man in red shirt against brightly painted wall in folk art colors of pink and blue; 4, 1920 antique typewriter in Leon Nicaragua hotel; 5, Female Sandinista on barber shop sign in Leon Nicaragua; 6-10, Scantily clad mannequins on Leon Nicaragua street; 11, View from Leon Cathedral of distant Nicaraguan volcanoes; 12, Shell display at surf camp on Pacific coast outside Leon; 13-14, Surfer sleeping in surf camp west of Leon on the Pacific Ocean; 15, Woman sleeping at Leon bus station.; 15 still image files (jpg)
    - Nicaragua, 2014, 1 folder (Box/folder 34/12)
      - Pamphlet reprint of folk hero Augusto Sandino's February 1931 manifesto, Light and Truth by CO-Press, Berkeley, California. Also June 2, 1928 Sandino interview by Max Grillo. Also maps of Ometepe Island and pamphlet about Finca Santo Domingo, AFC 2018/064: W-01
    - Nicaragua notebook, 2014, Notes surrounding an exploration of Sandino folk culture in Leon, Nicaragua, including side trips to Granada and Ometepe Island.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 35/1)
  - Optical media, Optical discs that originally housed digital files from afc2018064_dc004, afc2018064_dc005, afc2018064_dc006, afc2018064_dc007, and afc2018064_dc008.; 6 video discs (DVD) (Box 59)
Bibliography
Published works in this collection
Balistreri, Rosa. Canti di Sicilia. PDR RLPK 10018, 1988, sound cassette.
Banda de Música. Marchas Procescionales en Sevilla. Musivox, 1994, sound cassette.
Crossroads Children. Songs from Crossroads. Butterfly BT 1843, 1979, sound disc.
Hassel, Eva. Gelebte Interkulturalität: Weibliches Schreiben im Italo/Amerikanischen Kontext. Würzburg, Germany: Königshausen & Neumann, 2000.
Lawrence, John W., editor. West Wind Review: A Contemporary Journal of Literature 7 (Spring 1998).
Other related publications
Fazio, Venera and Delia De Santis, editors. Sweet Lemons: Writings with a Sicilian Accent. New York: Legas, 2004.
Lloyd, Susan. No Pictures in My Grave: A Spiritual Journey in Sicily. San Francisco: Mercury House, 1992.
Marino, Elisabetta. Ancestral Mothers, Feminine Icons, and Black Madonnas in the Works of Susan Caperna Lloyd. TestoeSenso (2019): 1-12.
Marino, Elisabetta. The Black Madonna in the Italian American Artistic Imagination. Acta Neophilologica 50, no. 1-2 (2017): 37-56.
Marino, Elisabetta. Searching for Identity: No Pictures in My Grave: A Spiritual Journey in Sicily. Journal of British and American Studies 24 (2018): 97-103.
Patrona, Theodora. Novels of Return: Ethnic Space in Contemporary Greek-American and Italian-American Literature. PhD dissertation, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece, February 2001.
Seffer, Valentina. Identity on the Threshold: The Myth of Persephone in Italian American Women's Memoir. PhD dissertation, University of Sydney, Australia, 2015.